Guide to the Investigation Files of the Rapp-Coudert Committee TAM.533
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Microfilm Reel List (with Cross-Reference to Original Box and Folder Locations), 1919-1953
  - Balet, Leonard F. (Art History Professor, Brooklyn College): Includes Correrspondence to Committee Denouncing Balet and Faculty Criticism of Balet's Lectures, 1939-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0001, Box-folder 13-RC505)
  - Miscellaneous: Includes Anonymous Letters to the Committee Denouncing "Subversive Individuals", Mar 1941-Sep 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0070, Box-folder 13-RC505a)
  - Howard Selsam Exhibits (Professor Brooklyn College): Includes Newspaper Clippings and Publications, Flyers of Selsam's Speeches for the Karl Marx Club, 1938-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0197, Box-folder 13-RC506,1)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941) #495-521: Includes Schools and the Crisis, The New York Teacher, American Federation of Teachers Membership Cards, 1934-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0358, Box-folder 13-RC506,2)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941) #416-457: Includes Newspaper Clippings from The Daily Worker, New York Herald Tribune, College Newsletter, 1934-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0505, Box-folder 13-RC506,3)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941) #1-85: Includes Workers School Announcement of Courses, Board of Education Resolution Expelling Isidore Begun and Mrs. Williena J. Burroughs, Teachers Union Minutes, 1933-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0547, Box-folder 13-RC506,4)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941) #374-415: Includes Young Communist Review, The Party Organizer, "An Open Letter to President Gideonse" (Brooklyn College), and Waivers of Immunity, 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0729, Box-folder 13-RC506,5)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941): Includes The Bulletin of the Anti-Fascist Association, Soviet Russia Todayr, Proceedings of the 10th Convention of the Communist Party, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0806, Box-folder 13-RC506,6)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941): Includes Flyers for the Karl Marx Society and Anti-War Groups, 1939-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0860, Box-folder 13-RC506,7)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941) Canning: Includes Notes and Clippings of The Daily Worker (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0873, Box-folder 13-RC506,8)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941): Includes The New York Teacher, The New Pioneer, and "Resume of Objectives of the Communist Party", 1933-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 34-0889, Box-folder 13-RC506,9)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941): Includes the Workers School Course Offerings and "Themes and Decisions of the 13th Plenium of the Executive Committee of the Communist International", 1937-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 35-0001, Box-folder 13-RC506,10)
  - Exhibits for Public Hearing (June 4-5, 1941) Canning and City College: Includes Teacher Worker, Harlem Lesson Plan, Correspondence to the Committee, Lists of Communists, 1937-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 35-0055, Box-folder 13-RC506,11)
  - Miscellaneous: Court Papers from Contempt Cases - Includes Brief for Respondents in Special Proceeding for Contempt, Committee vs. Howard Selsam, Maurice Ogur, Harry Slochower, Frederic Ewer, Murray Young, also Committee vs. Charles Hendley (President, Teachers Union) and Committee vs. Reinhold Class (Leader Brooklyn Group, Youth Division of German-American Bund), 1933-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 35-0101, Box-folder 13-RC506a(I))
  - Books and Pamphlets: Includes Germany Facts and Figures, The German Quarterly, Die Verburgerlichung der Detschen Kunst (Professor Leo Balet, Boston College), also List of Persons Subpoenaed, 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 35-0332, Box-folder 13-RC506a(II))
  - Stephen Politis: Includes Affidavit of Service, Warrant for Apprehension, Sep 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 35-0734, Box-folder 13-RC507,1)
  - People v. Morris U. Schappes (CCNY): Includes Respondents Brief Appellate Division New York Supreme Court, Memorandum People vs. Schappes, Board of High Education Charges vs. Schappes, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 35-0761, Box-folder 13-RC507,2)
  - John Little, Contempt Action: Includes Hearing Transcripts, Application for Contempt, Memorandum in Support of Motion to Commit for Contempt, Repondent's Memorandum, and Law Order to Show Cause, Jan 1941-Jul 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 36-0001, Box-folder 13-RC507,3)
  - Mark Graubard, Abraham Goldfield, World Tourists: Includes Orders of Apprehension, Warrants, and Application for Committee to Examine Grand Jury Minutes, Jan 1941-Mar 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 36-0220, Box-folder 13-RC507,4)
  - Withrow, Brooks Case: Includes Notice of Appeal, Application to Vacate Subpoenas, Order to Show Cause, and Opposing Affidavit, Jan 1941-Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 36-0293, Box-folder 13-RC507,5)
  - Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union): Includes Memorandum in Opposition to Motion to Commit for Contempt and Memorandum to Vacate Subpoena, Oct 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 36-0399, Box-folder 13-RC507,6)
  - Local 5, Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union) Cases: Includes Application to New York Supreme Court to Punish Hendley for Contempt, Briefs of the New York City Committee of the American Civil Liberties Union and the New York City Chapter of the National Lawyers Guild as Amicus Curiae, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 36-0460, Box-folder 14-RC508,1)
  - Local 5, Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union) Cases: Includes Brief for Respondent in Application to Punish Hendley for Contempt, Papers on Appeal, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 36-0623, Box-folder 14-RC508,2)
  - Local 537 New York College Teachers Union: Court Records of Committee Contempt Proceedings against Bella Dodd (Custodian of Chapter Records) and Robert K Speer (President of Chapter) - Includes Memorandum on Behalf of Petitioner in Application to Compel Production of Certain Records of the New York College Teachers Union Local 537, Hearing Proceedings, Feb 1941-May 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 37-0001, Box-folder 14-RC509)
  - Bella Dodd (Custodian of Records, Local 537) and Robert Speer (President, Local 537) vs. Knickerbocker Broadcasting Company, Joint Legislative Commission (Rapp Coudert): Includes Statement by Paul Windels Regarding Committee's Inverstigation of Anonymous Individuals' Identities During Citizens Committee for the Defense of Free Public Education Broadcasts, Temporary Restraining Order Issued Against Committee, April 1941-May 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 37-0239, Box-folder 14-RC510)
  - Local 5, Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union) Cases Regarding Contempt Proceedings: Includes Hendley's Application to New York Supreme Court to Vacate Subpoena, Application to Punish Hendley, Order to Show Cause, Hearing Testimony, and Notice of Appeal, Oct 1940-Dec 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 37-0405, Box-folder 14-RC511)
  - Contempt Action: Reinhold G. Class (Leader Brooklyn Group, Youth Division of German-American Bund) - Includes Hearing Proceedings, Order to Show Cause, and Motion to Punish, May 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 37-0735, Box-folder 14-RC512)
  - Contempt Proceedings: Selsam, Ogur, Slochower, Ewen, Young (Professors at Brooklyn College) - Includes Application to Punish from New York State Supreme Court, Hearing Proceedings, Exhibits, Depositions, and Judgement, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 38-0001, Box-folder 14-RC513)
  - Digest of Private Testimony: Includes Digests of Testimony and Memoranda, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 38-0277, Box-folder 14-RC514)
  - Private Hearing Exhibits: Includes Stock Certificates for Y and H Realty, Photographs, Flyers, Pamphlets, and Correspondence, 1929-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 38-0489, Box-folder 14-RC515)
  - Digest of Private Testimonies of Students (Former and Current Students, Alumni): Includes Digests, Editorial Summaries of Interviews, and Lists of Students Engaged in Subversive Activities, Jan 1941-Nov 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 38-0574, Box-folder 14-RC516)
  - Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union): Includes Court of Appeals Briefs, and Papers, Amicus Curiae Briefs, and Opinions, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 38-0852, Box-folder 15-RC517,1)
  - Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union): Includes Court of Appeals Briefs of Amicus Curiae, Teachers Union Appeal Papers, and Brief for Respondent, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 39-0001, Box-folder 15-RC517,2)
  - Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union): Includes Court of Appeals Records, Appellants Brief, Notice of Motion and "Handbook Teachers Union Local 5", 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 39-0210, Box-folder 15-RC518)
  - Various Publications Between Folders: Includes Policy of Public Works under the Fascist Regime (1935), What Italy is Doing for Islam in Africa, American Neutrality Legislation Threatens the Collapse of Western Civilization (1936), Quando il Mondo era Roma, and VVV Magazine (1942 no. 1), 1932-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 39-0547, Box-folder 15-RC518a)
  - Louie May Miner (Assistant Professor of English, Brooklyn College): Includes Supreme Court Records of Louie May Miner vs. the Committee, Memoranda in Support of Motion to Dismiss Complaint, Notice to Produce Summons, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 40-0001, Box-folder 15-RC519)
  - Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union): Briefs and Legal Papers - Includes Index of Papers Relating to Application to Punish Hendley for Contempt, Depositions, and Hearing Proceedings, Oct 1940-Nov 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 40-0137, Box-folder 15-RC520)
  - Selsam, Ogur, Slochower, Ewen, and Young (Professors at Brooklyn College): Includes Memorandum in Support of Motion before Supreme Court to Punish for Contempt, Order to Show Cause, Summons, and Complaints, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 40-0435, Box-folder 15-RC521,1)
  - Photo Negatives of Rubin Gotesky and Young Materials, Jan 1941-Apr 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 40-0580, Box-folder 15-RC521,2)
  - Hearing Transcripts: A, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 40-0624, Box-folder 15-RC522)
  - Hearing Transcripts: B, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 41-0001, Box-folder 16-RC523)
  - Hearing Transcripts: C, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 41-0396, Box-folder 16-RC524)
  - Hearing Transcripts: D, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 41-0703, Box-folder 16-RC525)
  - Hearing Transcripts: E, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 41-1202, Box-folder 16-RC526)
  - Hearing Transcripts: F, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 42-0001, Box-folder 16-RC527)
  - Hearing Transcripts: G Part I, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 42-0217, Box-folder 16-RC528)
  - Hearing Transcripts: G Part II, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 42-0450, Box-folder 16-RC529)
  - Hearing Transcripts: H, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 42-0758, Box-folder 16-RC530)
  - Hearing Transcripts: I, May 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 43-0001, Box-folder 16-RC531)
  - Hearing Transcripts: J, Jan 1941-Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 43-0014, Box-folder 16-RC532)
  - Hearing Transcripts: K, Jan 1941-Sep 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 43-0095, Box-folder 16-RC533)
  - Hearing Transcripts: L (original numbering error), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 43-0230, Box-folder 16-RC535)
  - Hearing Transcripts: M Part I (original numbering error), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 43-0526, Box-folder 16-RC534)
  - Hearing Transcripts: M Part II, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 43-0757, Box-folder 17-RC536)
  - Hearing Transcripts: N, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 43-1064, Box-folder 17-RC537)
  - Hearing Transcripts: O (original numbering error), Jun 1941-Nov 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 44-0001, Box-folder 17-RC539)
  - Hearing Transcripts: P (original numbering error), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 44-0096, Box-folder 17-RC538)
  - Hearing Transcripts: R, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 44-0259, Box-folder 17-RC540)
  - Hearing Transcripts: S Part I, Jan 1941-Dec 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 44-0409, Box-folder 17-RC541)
  - Hearing Transcripts: S Part II, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 44-0667, Box-folder 17-RC542)
  - Hearing Transcripts: S Part III: Includes Photo Negatives, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 44-0894, Box-folder 17-RC543)
  - Hearing Transcripts: S Part IV, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 45-0001, Box-folder 17-RC544)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Frank Boylan (Administrative Assistant, De Witt Clinton High School), Oct 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 45-0433, Box-folder 17-RC545)
  - Hearing Transcripts: T, Apr 1941-Nov 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 45-0470, Box-folder 17-RC546)
  - Hearing Transcripts: W, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 45-0551, Box-folder 17-RC547)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Y - Young, Feb 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 45-0904, Box-folder 17-RC548)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Z, Apr 1941-May 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 45-0923, Box-folder 17-RC549)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Bella V. Dodd (Custodian of Records, Teachers Union), Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union), May 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 45-0987, Box-folder 17-RC550)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Bernard David Nino Gerbanier (Professor, Brooklyn College), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 46-0001, Box-folder 17-RC551)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Francis T. Williamson (Instructor in History, CCNY), Feb 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 46-0271, Box-folder 17-RC552)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Abraham Goodhartz (Registrar's Office, Brooklyn College), Feb 1941-Mar 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 46-0299, Box-folder 17-RC553)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Ralph De Sola (Naturalist), Nov 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 46-0333, Box-folder 17-RC554)
  - Hearing Transcripts: High School Principals, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 46-0378, Box-folder 18-RC555)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Abraham and Joseph Goldfield (Printers) - Includes Editorialized Summaries of Interviews, Feb 1941-Mar 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 46-0843, Box-folder 18-RC556)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Rheinhold G. Class (Leader Brooklyn Group, Youth Division of German-American Bund), May 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 46-0967, Box-folder 18-RC557)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Digest of Private Testimony of William Martin Canning - Includes Index and List of Subversive Individuals, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 47-0001, Box-folder 18-RC558)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Sabbaticals - Includes Testimony of Teachers Union Members in Public Schools on Leaves of Absence and Sabbaticals, Mar 1941-Jul 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 47-0872, Box-folder 18-RC559)
  - Hearing Transcripts: "List of Those in School Systems on whom there is Evidence" - Includes List of Individuals named by Canning that have and have not Testified, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 48-0001, Box-folder 18-RC560,1)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Photo Negatives of List "Summary of Evidence Secured against Individuals now in the Educational Systems", undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 48-0248, Box-folder 18-RC560,2)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Individuals - Includes Campbell, Colligan, Evansohn, Flynn, Gideonse, Klapper, Lazarus, Lewinson, Lombardo, Mack, Marshall, Seelman, Shuster, Store, Tead, Tuttle, Wright (all Members of the Board of Education or Presidents of City Colleges), Nov 1941-Dec 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 48-0412, Box-folder 18-RC561)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Digest of Private Testimony of William Martin Canning - Includes Index and List of Subversive Individuals (repeat of file RC-558), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 49-0001, Box-folder 19-RC562)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Fascists I, Feb 1941-Mar 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 49-0082, Box-folder 19-RC563)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Fascists II, Mar 1941-Apr 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 49-0395, Box-folder 19-RC564)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Nazi I, Mar 1941-Jul 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 49-0757, Box-folder 19-RC565)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Nazi II, Jul 1941-Aug 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 50-0001, Box-folder 19-RC566)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Graubard (Zoologist, Former Member of Communist Party), Feb 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 50-0186, Box-folder 19-RC567)
  - Hearing Transcripts:Testimony of Board of Education (overlap with RC 561), Nov 1941-Dec 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 50-0232, Box-folder 19-RC568)
  - Hearing Transcripts:Testimony of City Colleges' Presidents (overlap with RC 561), Dec 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 50-0828, Box-folder 19-RC569)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Students (New York City High School and College Students and Alumni)(I), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 51-0001, Box-folder 19-RC570)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Students (New York City High School and College Students and Alumni)(II), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 51-0574, Box-folder 19-RC571)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Students (New York City High School and College Students and Alumni)(III), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 52-0001, Box-folder 20-RC572)
  - Newspaper Clippings on Italian Fascism: Includes The New York Times, PM, New York Herald Tribune, The Saturday Evening Post, Look, New York Journal American (on assassination of John Arena), 1940-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 52-0522, Box-folder 20-RC572a)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Kemkit (Scientific Corporation that supplied material to City College, owned in part by members of CCNY's Chemistry Department), Jul 1941-Aug 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 52-0553, Box-folder 20-RC573)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Kemkit (Scientific Corporation that supplied material to City College, owned in part by members of CCNY's Chemistry Department), Jul 1941-Aug 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 52-0850, Box-folder 20-RC574,1)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Kemkit (Scientific Corporation that supplied material to City College, owned in part by members of CCNY's Chemistry Department), Jul 1941-Aug 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 53-0001, Box-folder 20-RC574,2)
  - Card Index A-F (index of individuals and corporations typed on notecards), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 53-0375, Box-folder 20-RC575,1)
  - Card Index G-R (index of individuals and corporations typed on notecards), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 54-0001, Box-folder 20-RC575,2)
  - Card Index S-Z (index of individuals and corporations typed on notecards), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 55-0001, Box-folder 20-RC575,3)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Kemkit (Scientific Corporation that supplied material to City College, owned in part by members of CCNY's Chemistry Department), Jul 1941-Aug 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 55-0663, Box-folder 21-RC576)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Sherman, Annette (Mrs. Gottsegen, Clerical Assistant, CCNY), Jan 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 55-0823, Box-folder 21-RC577)
  - Hearing Transcripts: Oscar Zeichner (Instructor, CCNY), Feb 1941-Mar 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 55-0942, Box-folder 21-RC578)
  - Testimony of William Martin Canning (Committee Informant, CCNY), Jan 1941-Feb 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 55-1009, Box-folder 21-RC579)
  - "A" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee: Includes ACLU Memorandum to Committee and Flyers, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 55-1297, Box-folder 21-RC580)
  - Aaron, G. B. (Assistant Counsel for Committee): Correspondence with the Committee, 1941-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 55-1356, Box-folder 21-RC581)
  - "B" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee: Includes Board of Education, 1941-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 55-1365, Box-folder 21-RC582)
  - Board of Education: Correspondence with the Committee: Includes Material on the Isidore Begun and Williana J. Burroughs Cases, 1933-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0001, Box-folder 21-RC583)
  - Board of Higher Education: Correspondence with the Committee, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0043, Box-folder 21-RC584)
  - Board of Elections: Correspondence with the Committee, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0047, Box-folder 21-RC585)
  - Complaints: Anonymous - Includes Letters Denouncing Teachers at Schools and Colleges as Subversive, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0052, Box-folder 21-RC586)
  - Complaints: Includes Letters Denouncing Teachers at Schools and Colleges as Subversive, Letters Protesting Activities of the Committee, The American Character Builder, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0060, Box-folder 21-RC587)
  - "C" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee: Includes Letters to Harold G. Campbell (Superintendent of Schoools) on Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union) Case, 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0198, Box-folder 21-RC588)
  - "D" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0278, Box-folder 21-RC589)
  - "E" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1941-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0301, Box-folder 21-RC590)
  - "F" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0318, Box-folder 21-RC591)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: Correspondence with the Committee - Includes Memoranda of Interviews with FBI Agents, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0334, Box-folder 21-RC592)
  - "G" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1932-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0343, Box-folder 21-RC593)
  - Graubard, Dr. Mark (Zoologist, former Communist Party Member): Correspondence with the Committee - Includes Editorialized Summary of Interview, Jan 1941-Feb 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0430, Box-folder 21-RC594)
  - "H" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0441, Box-folder 21-RC595)
  - "J" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, Apr 1941-Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0463, Box-folder 21-RC596)
  - "K" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1940-1944 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0467, Box-folder 21-RC597)
  - "L" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1940-1944 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0508, Box-folder 21-RC598)
  - Dr. Henry E. Linville (Executive Director, Teachers Guild): Correspondence with the Committee, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0528, Box-folder 21-RC599)
  - Ben Mandel (Former Research Director for Dies Committee, State Department): Correspondence with the Committee - Includes Editorialized Summaries of Interviews with Mandel, Memoradum of Trip to Washington, Mandel's Lists of College Professors, Organizations where Membership Would Serve as Evidence of Commmunist Activity, Possible Informants, and How to Identify Communists, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0546, Box-folder 21-RC600)
  - "M" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee: Includes Free Earl Browder, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0615, Box-folder 21-RC601)
  - "N" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1940-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0680, Box-folder 21-RC602)
  - "P" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, Jan 1941-Oct 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0696, Box-folder 21-RC603)
  - Protests Against the Committee: Correspondence with the Committee - Includes Letters of Protests against Methods and Aims of the the Investigation, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0722, Box-folder 21-RC604)
  - Protests Against the Committee: Correspondence with the Committee - Includes New Masses, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0942, Box-folder 21-RC605)
  - "R" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0975, Box-folder 21-RC606)
  - "S" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee, 1938-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 56-0986, Box-folder 21-RC607)
  - Letters Regarding "Subversives": Anonymous Correspondence with the Committee Denouncing Individuals for Subversive Activities, 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 57-0001, Box-folder 21-RC608)
  - "T" Letters: Correspondence with the Committee - Includes Teacher Worker, 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 57-0094, Box-folder 21-RC609)